SAULO MARCOS CORRÊA Senior Software Developer

CONTACT INFORMATION

Email: sauloejrv@gmail.com

Phone: (+55) 51 99721-7594

Location: Novo Hamburgo, RS - Brazil

LinkedIn:linkedin.com/in/saulo-marcos-correa-621898143/

SUMMARY OF QUALIFICATIONS

I have over 14 years of experience in software development, working on several projects. I master the life cycle of applications from conception to delivery and guarantee with the client. I seek to bring quality and security practices to projects aiming at the stability and observability of the product, as well as the prevention of failures. I work on migrating monolithic systems in microservices architecture, messaging, and development with backend and frontend. I work on integration demands with third-party services, establishing integrations in the various platforms available on the market.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Stefanini Consulting and IT Advisory Senior Developer Analyst 06/2021 - present

Technologies: Cloud Foundry, AngularJS, .NET (Framework, microservices, core, EF core, CronJobs, MVC), Oracle, MS SQL Server, Redis Cache, Apache Kafka, GitLab.

Activities: Working from home in a global team of a US company in the computer industry. Member of a team that owns 3 applications, working in Scrum with dailies, planning, and retrospectives. Technical reference in dotnet and frontend. I worked in a global system that supports purchase orders from Latin America, processing and directing invoices according to business rules. Participation in migrating legacy systems to modern architecture standards, security, scalability, high availability, and observability monitoring. I worked on maintaining monolithic ASP.NET MVC and MS SQL Server systems.

Tinotech Informática Analyst Developer 03/2019 - 06/2021

Technologies: .NET (Framework, core, EF, EF core), AngularJS, SQL Server, Git.

Activities: Home Office - Assigned to a large leading client in the area of technology

for retail, with an agile development process. I worked on the development of a nationwide sales portal and application support.

Feevale University

Systems Analyst

04/2011 - 03/2019

Technologies: .Net (MVC, EF, WinForms, WebForms, WCF, Razor, Windows Services), SQL Server, jQuery.

Activities: I worked on several desktop and web projects for a Brazilian university, including improvements to the course registration and entrance exam process, the main tool used to recruit students at the university. The collaboration resulted in the modernization of the process, generating user-friendly interfaces and resource optimization, improving performance and data availability.

WT Prime

Web Developer

01/2010 - 04/2011

Technologies: PHP, JavaScript, MySQL.

Activities: Development and maintenance of websites using PHP, JavaScript, and

MySQL.

Master Industrial Equipment - ByMaster

Electronics Technician

05/2008 - 01/2010

I worked with activities and technologies specific to industrial automation and electronics, which are no longer the focus of my professional career today.

Meta IT Services

IT Trainee

08/2006 - 04/2008

Technologies: Informix/4GL, Informix database.

Activities: I worked in the software factory model for a large Brazilian client in the insurance industry. The production of codes for batch processing, reports, and visual screens followed strict quality review processes.

ACADEMIC BACKGROUND

Bachelor's Degree in Computer Science
Feevale University
Completed in 2018

Electronics Technician and High School
Liberato Salzano Vieira da Cunha Technical School Foundation
Completed in 2009

PROJECTS AND PUBLICATIONS

Academic Research: Computer Graphics, Feevale University

Published Article: IEEE Latin America Transactions, "Model for Automatic Generation

of Difficulty Curves in Digital Games"

https://latamt.ieeer9.org/index.php/transactions/article/view/5989

LANGUAGES

Portuguese: NativeEnglish: Intermediate